thetoyshop.com 2019-09-10

# Privacy | TheToyShop.com | The Toyshop Site

We’re committed to protecting our customers’ personal data – old and new. We’ll always keep your data safe, up to date and only ever use it in the ways we describe below.

The same policy promise applies whether you shop with us on The Entertainer website - TheToyShop.com, or The Early Learning Centre website - ELC.co.uk

## Here's what you need to know...

  * We’ll always keep your personal data safe and secure – it’s number one priority to us
  * We’ll only ever use your data to improve your experience or complete an order you have placed with us
  * We’ll only ever use your data for marketing if you have told us you want us to – and we promise to never SPAM you
  * If we no longer need your personal data we will delete it – we love to keep our systems clean of cobwebs!

## How we use your information

Click on the buttons below to find out more about how we use your information.

## Your name & contact details (phone number, email, address)

### Why we collect it

  * It would be impossible to send your online order without this information.
  * To update you on your order
  * To update you on the latest products, sales and store information in your area
  * Fraud prevention

### How we use it

  * We use name and address info to create a postage label and may share phone numbers and emails with our couriers so they can send you tracking updates.
  * We will send you transactional service messages via email or text to update you on the status of your order and let you know when it's on its way!
  * We will only send you marketing messages via email, text or through adverts on other websites if you have given us clear consent to do so. You'll be able to choose to receive The Entertainer marketing messages, Early Learning Centre messages or both.
  * To help us detect and prevent fraud.

## Your child's information (name, age, DOB, gender)

### Why we collect it

  * Birthday Club sign up

### How we use it

  * To understand what products you may be after and serve you the best recommendations for your child's age.

## Your payment and billing information 

### Why we collect it

  * To take payment and process refunds when needed
  * Fraud prevention

### How we use it

  * To fulfil our contract with you and make sure you get the items you’ve ordered. 
  * To help us detect and prevent fraud. 

## Your contact history with us (customer service calls, live web chats, social media posts)

### Why we collect it

  * Provide customer service support
  * In order to train new staff

### How we use it

  * You expect the best level of customer service from our team. To allow us to do this we keep a history of all correspondence so you don’t need to explain everything that’s happened each time you speak to us.
  * In order to provide the best customer service we're always looking for ways to improve - these conversations allow us to learn and develop our customer support.

## Purchase history and saved baskets

### Why we collect it

  * To sell you things that you want
  * To sell you things we think you may want
  * Returns & refunds

### How we use it

  * Without items in your basket you can't buy anything on the site - you have to tell us what you want!
  * We may offer toy suggestions based on your purchase history and abandoned baskets - this helps you find related products to what you're interested in. 
  * We always hope you love your purchases, but in case you don't, we need to know what you bought in order to process your return or refund. 

## Your laptop/mobile/browser details (IP address, location services, how you behave on our website)

### Why we collect it

  * To improve the online experience you have with us
  * To protect our website & all its users

### How we use it

  * We need to know what helps you to shop faster and better in order to improve your experience on our site.
  * To help us detect and prevent fraud.

## Your responses to surveys, competitions

### Why we collect it

  * To run engaging competitions for our customers.
  * To improve your overall experience using information collected from customer feedback surveys.

### How we use it

  * We need your entry in order to count it as part of our prize draw mechanic for competitions.
  * We take your suggestions, analyse them and put the best ones into practice to improve the experience for you and all customers.

## Sharing your information

We do not sell _any_ of your personal data to any third parties. However, we do share your data with a select few companies in order to complete your contract with us and provide you with the best possible service. These include:

  * Our trusted partners that get your order to you – this includes our order delivery companies
  * Marketing agencies who help us get our products in front of the right person
  * Law enforcement and fraud prevention agencies

## Marketing

We only use your information for marketing purposes when specific consent has been provided by you agreeing for us to do so, i.e., you have ticked the subscription check box at checkout.

You can unsubscribe from marketing communication at any time by:

  * Updating your preferences in ‘My Account’
  * Clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link in an email
  * Contacting our customer service team

We may also show you The Entertainer or Early Learning Centre adverts when browsing other websites. We do this to help you easily find the products you may like.

The adverts you see will be based on information we hold on you or your previous use of TheToyShop.com or ELC.co.uk – this means you may see products you have previously browsed or promotions we think you’ll be interested in.

## Your data, your rights

You have the right to:

  * Request a copy of the information held on you
  * Correct the information we hold on you
  * Have the information we hold on you deleted 

In order to act upon one of your above rights, or if you just have a question, please write to:

The Customer Services Manager  
RE. GDPR  
The Entertainer (Amersham) Ltd.  
Boughton Business Park  
Bell Lane  
Little Chalfont  
BUCKS   
HP6 6GL 

Or email:  

## Legitimate interests

Under GDPR data law there are a number of lawful reasons for us to use (or 'process') your personal information. One of the lawful reasons is called 'legitimate interests'. Broadly speaking Legitimate Interests means that we can process your personal information if: 

  * We have a genuine and legitimate reason _and_ we are not harming any of your rights and interests.

Some typical examples of when we might use the approach are for preventing fraud, digital marketing, maintaining the security of our system, data analytics and enhancing, modifying or improving our services.

As ever, you can opt-out at any time.

## Other websites

Our website and marketing communications may contain links to other websites run by carefully selected partners. We’ll make it clear you’re visiting a partner website before you click.

We don’t run these websites so we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting them. Please look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question before supplying any personal details.

## Cookies

Our website uses cookies to collect information. A cookie is a piece of text which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, your browser adds that text in a small file.

Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. For example, a cookie makes it easier to shop by remembering your email address so you don’t have to re-enter it each time you visit.

Cookies also enable us to check which pages are the most popular on the site and how visitors use our site. A cookie does not give us access to your computer.

The 'help' menu in most web browsers will tell you how you can be informed when you receive a new cookie or how to disable cookies altogether. However, we recommend that you leave cookies turned on as they allow you to access some of the most useful features of TheToyShop.com and ELC.co.uk.
